# 大家好 你看 今天這個 卸的 卸的是那個助農產品哦
Hi everyone! Look! Today, this is, we're unloading, unloading the agricultural products from our poverty alleviation project.
# 兄弟家的蜂蜜 都拉去檢測了
My buddy's honey, was sent for quality inspection.
# 你看這個 合格証書 全都檢測合格
Look! These are, certificates of approval. All have passed the inspection.
# 這個 滿滿的一車啊
Here is, a whole lorry.
# 現在幫忙搬一下 太多啦 一大車
Now I'm gonna help them. There are too many, one whole lorry.
# 這一箱差不多有60斤重
Each box weighs almost 30 kilograms.
# 差不多60斤
Almost 30 kilograms
# 誒呦 那麼重的
Eyo! It's so heavy!
# 不要太高 太高了不好下
Not too high! You can't unload them if it's too high.
# 等下 會翻掉的哦
It might, even flip over, you know.
# 這車不好啦的
Pulling this cart is no easy task.
# 啊~
Ah~
# 這差不多五六十斤
It's twenty five or even thirty kilograms.
# 那麼重
So heavy
# 兄弟都 都是從農戶手上收的
My buddies have, these are all collected from the farmers.
# 要不是他收了 農戶就不好賣
The farmers have very limited channels to sell their products if my buddy is not collecting from them.
# 好快哦 一車馬上就卸掉了
It doesn't take long! We're about to have one whole lorry unloaded.
# 裝多一車就夠了 先把它拉進去
One more turn will end our job. Let's pull it inside first.
# 聽說兄弟家養了很多土雞土鴨還有土鵝
I heard that my buddy is keeping a lot of free range poultry here, like, chicks, ducks and geese as well.
# 更多的是那個魚
What's even more are the fish.
# 一池塘都是魚 搞一瓶蜂蜜
The whole pond is filled with fish. I've taken a jar of honey with me.
# 送兄弟 他家就在這裡
I'm gonna give it to my buddy. Here's his place.
# 你看 蓮花 哎呀
Look! Lotus! Aya!
# 這種 這個 有一個蓮子 可以吃的哦 這個蓮子
This is, this one, there's a lotus seed. The lotus seed is edible, you know.
# 很好吃的
And it's really tasty.
# 絕對OK
Absolutely OK!
# 掉下去啦 別以為我不要你
It fell. Don't think that I'm letting you go.
# 掉下去我也要把你檢回來
I'm gonna pick you up, even you fell.
# 這個蓮子 有肉哦
This lotus seed, the inner part is edible.
# 剛剛好大的哦 很嫩的 這種蓮子
It's just huge! This kind of lotus seed is really young and tender.
# 一點都不苦
It's not bitter at all.
# 還有好多啊
There are still a lot!
# 等一下來 等一下
Later, I'll come again later.
# 先找一下兄弟
Let me figure out my buddy's whereabouts first.
# 問他去哪裡啦
I'm gonna ask them where he is.
# 兄弟又不在 把這個蜂蜜一下在這裡
My buddy is not around. Let me leave the honey here in a while.
# 這是他家的魚塘
This is his pond.
# 好大呀
It's huge!
# 應該有幾十畝哦
There should be several hectares.
# 那裡面還有
It's all the way over there.
# 我去看一下他的雞 我的雞就養在那裡面
I'm gonna have a look at his chicks. He's keeping his chicks there inside.
# 看一下
Let me see,
# 好不好吃了
if they taste good.
# 蜂蜜放到這裡先
I leave the honey here first.
# 你看 這兄弟的大門
Look! This is my buddy's gate.
# 這也能網雞 連我都網不住 還能網雞
Does he think that it can fence up the chicks? It can't even fence me off, let alone the chicks.
# 你看 這裡有山胡椒的果子哦
Look! Here are the fruits of wild pepper.
# 好香的
It smells so good!
# 神清氣爽
Refreshing!
# 你看 兄弟家的雞 就在這裡哦
Look! My buddy's chicks, are right here.
# 終於看到啦
I can see them finally.
# 沒帶東西 拍抓不到
Without any tools, I wonder if I can catch them.
# 抄網都沒有這裡
Here's not even a catch net.
# 怎麼抓嘞
How can I catch them?
# 你看 還有這個抄網
Look! Here's still a catch net.
# 沒這個抄網的話 怎麼抓都抓不到
There's simply no way to catch them without the catch net.
# 你看
Look!
# 在那裡
Over there!
# 不要走 這裡有好吃的 快點過來
Don't run away! Here's some very good food! Come here!
# 快點過來呦
Come here, guys!
# 你以為 你以為你跑很掉嗎
You think, you think that you can run away from me?
# 翻山越嶺
Over the mountains and the sea,
# 把你抓起來
I'm gonna catch you!
# 這雞跑的好快呀
These chicks run really fast.
# 抓都抓不到
I can't catch them.
# 到這裡肯定跑不了
There's no escape here.
# 你看
Look!
# 抓到它雞窩裡面啦
They've run into the roost.
# 把它趕到雞窩裡面啦
I've chased them off back to the roost.
# 現在就跑不了啦
There's no escape now.
# 老公雞
Old rooster
# 老閹雞 嘿嘿
Old capon, hay hay!
# 誒呀
Eya!
# 那麼重
It's so heavy!
# 你看 這個是閹雞來的
Look! This is a capon.
# 閹雞才好吃
Capon tastes the best.
# 差不多五六斤 七八斤都可能有
It almost three, or even four kilograms.
# 那麼重
It's so heavy.
# 很結實的哦
It's muscular, you know.
# 打你兩下 追了那麼就[SIC]才追到你
Beat you hard! You made me chase after you for such a long time!
# 閉嘴
Shut up!
# 別叫啦 沒人來救你的
Stop yelping! No one's gonna help you.
# 叫叫叫叫叫
Yelp, yelp, yelp and yelp
# 誒呀
Eya!
# 這裡有雞蛋哦
Here are some eggs!
# 這種雞蛋
These eggs,
# 還可以的這個 五黑雞
are not bad. These are, laid by,
# 下的蛋
black chickens.
# 就叫五黑雞蛋
So they're called, black chicken eggs.
# 誒呀 那麼多刺
Eya! So many spikes
# 你看 把這個雞抓回來啦 在在籠子上
Look! I've now taken the chicken back and it's now in the cage.
# 我看到它好孤單啊
It seems very lonely to me.
# 搞個鴨子給它做飯
Let me fetch it a duck, to cook for it.
# 在這裡有抄網
Here's a catch net.
# 鴨子這裡有幾隻
And there are a couple of ducks.
# 你看 鴨子
Look! Ducks!
# 誒呀 搞得一身都是水
Eya! It made me wet all over the body.
# 你看 雞跟鴨在一起 它們有伴啦 也不叫啦
Look! The chicken and duck are now together. They have a companion now and so they're not yelping anymore.
# 好 等一下我去看一下有沒有魚釣
Alright! Let me see if I can catch a fish in a while.
# 在那邊 那邊應該有魚
Over there. There must be fish.
# 你看 這兄弟的 兄弟這個玉米
Look! These are my buddy's, my buddy's corns.
# 搞點他的玉米來釣一下
I'm gonna fish with his corns.
# 這裡好多大魚的
Here are a lot of very big fish.
# 我也不怎會釣魚
I'm not really that good at fishing.
# 攝影小哥才會
Mr. Cameraman is the real master.
# 好啦 奶遠啦
Good! It's far enough.
# 釣魚要有耐心的哦 如果沒有耐心的話釣不到的
Patience is essential for fishing. Without patience, there's no chance of catching any fish.
# 釣到一條
I got one,
# 不知道甚東西
but only God knows what it is.
# 你看 它一直在拉
Look! It keeps on pulling.
# 我一扔下去它就咬到啦 我還以為沒沉到底那
It bit the hook soon after I had threw out the hook. I even thought that the hook was still floating.
# 這個是甚麼東西 你看
What is it? Look!
# 好大的力氣啊 杆子都彎啦
It's pulling so hard! The pole is already bent.
# 過來過來過來
Come here, come here, come here
# 誒呦 可以 過來過來過來 過來 過來
Eya! Yea! Come here, come here, come here. Here, here!
# 這甚麼魚
What fish is it?
# 青魚 青草魚
Green, green grass carp
# 這種比草魚 肉要緊
Its meat is, firmer that that of grass carps.
# 嘿 別動 別動
Hey! Don't move, don't move!
# 我們那邊叫石草魚
It's called rock grass carp at my place.
# 吞進去啦
Has it swallowed the hook?
# 鈎都掉了
The hook is gone!
# 它咬著不放
It's not spitting it out.
# 這個拿回去
Let's take it back.
# 拿回去 這個拿來加餐
Take it back. We'll have an extra dish.
# 你看 這個兄弟貢獻的炭哦
Look! This is the charcoal, contributed by my buddy.
# 他說給一箱炭給我
He said that he's giving me a box of charcoal.
# 這個炭是
This charcoal is,
# 最便直的
the cheapest one.
# 他說 他說贊助我
He said, he said that he would sponsor me.
# 雞也不讚助一個 鴨也不贊助一個
But he sponsors me neither a chicken, nor a duck.
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 燒了一下我
I got burnt.
# 你看 這個雞和鴨都已經處理好啦
Look! The chicken and the duck have already been processed.
# 把它先
Let me first,
# 先這
I mean,
# 要先砍碎一點 要不然等下烤不 烤不了的
I need to chop it a few times first. Otherwise, it wouldn't be possible to grill it.
# 這個
I ah,
# 多割一下
slice it a few more times.
# 好啦 姿劫要擺好來
Alright! The posture is important.
# 腳指卡在這裡就行啦
I think I can simply hinge the toe here.
# 嘿 搞定 你看
Hey! Done! Look!
# 這個姿勢好
It's a nice posture.
# 沒有兩個夾子 有兩個夾子就
It's too bad that I don't have another grilling net. If I had another net, I would,
# 左手一隻雞 右手一隻鴨
have a chicken on my left hand, and a duck on my right hand.
# 現在只能一個一個烤
But now I can only grill them one by one.
# 哇 好香啊
Wa! It smells so good!
# 好香味出來啦
I can already smell it.
# 站的好累呀
Standing is really tiring.
# 著火啦
It's on fire.
# 好燙啊
It so hot!
# 刷點油
Spray some oil
# 燙的更香
It smells much better.
# 這火太大啦 這個
The fire is too strong, here.
# 哎呀 就燒黑啦
Aya! So it's burnt.
# 放到這裡來
Put it on this side.
# 太快啦 一下子就燒黑啦 太多油啦
It caught me off guard. It got burnt all of a sudden. There was too much oil.
# 你看 這個 黑掉啦
Look! Here, it's burnt.
# 誒呀 烤東西不好烤哦
Eya! Grilling is never an easy task.
# 哎喲 這個蜂蜜來咯
Ayo! Here comes the honey!
# 加點蜂蜜
Put some honey.
# 香香甜甜
It's sweet with a scent of honey,
# 酸 香甜苦辣都有
so there's sourness, fragrance, sweetness, bitterness and spiciness, everything.
# 哇 下雨啦 要不要這樣子啊
Wa! It rains! C'mon, it's not nice!
# 我鴨子都還沒烤 魚也還沒烤
I've not yet grilled the duck, nor the fish.
# 都直接用那個
Let's simply use the,
# 直接去煮算啦 不能 不能烤啦
I mean, cook them right away. No more, no more grilling.
# 蜜汁燒雞 煮好啦
Honey grilled chicken. Done!
# 來 搞點孜然粉
Yea, put some, cummin powder.
# 味道杠杠的
C'est délicieux!
# 好 先看一下
Alright! Let me see,
# 好不好吃
if it taste good.
# 哇 真的不錯耶
Wa! It's really not bad!
# 味道還可以喲
It tastes rather good.
# 這個不是
It's no,
# 不是騙人的
no kidding.
# 下雨啦 下雨啦
It rains, it rains!
# 趕快收 趕快收
Hurry up! Grab everything!
# 等下 等下想吃
Don't let, don't,
# 雞都沒得吃啦
don't let the rain spoil the chicken.
# 先把雞搞走先
Let me take the chicken away first.
# 剛剛下了大雨 又起了大風
The rain just poured and the wind blew heavily.
# 幸好把這個雞搶 搶回來啦
Fortunately, I've grabbed, grabbed the chicken back.
# 要不然都淋雨啦
Otherwise it would be soaked.
# 嘗一下這個
Let me try the,
# 雞腿 看一下怎麼樣
chicken leg, and see how it is.
# 嗯
Um!
# 你看 全熟啦
Look! It's well done.
# 那個鴨子跟魚就沒辦烤啦
There's to way to grill the duck and the fish.
# 直接煮啦
We'll simply cook them.
# 煮了之後
Cooking them,
# 就直接
it means,
# 紅燒魚
braised fish.
# 哎 搞一個雞腿吃一下
Ya! Let me have a chicken leg.
# 哎喲 可以喲
Aya! Not bad!
# 熟啦
It's done.
# 就是有點黑
It's just a bit burnt,
# 有點難看
and a bit ugly.
# 嗯
Um!
# 可以喲
Not bad!
# 特別好吃
It's exceptionnaly good!
# 刮風又大 下 又刮風又下雨
Strong wind is, rain, the wind and the rain comes again.
# 刷了蜂蜜特別好吃 真的
It tastes exceptionally good with the honey. No kidding.